Smit Panchal

Portfolio 226-899-6632 smit.1999.panchal@gmail.com

in Panchal-Smit

SmitPanchal1999

SUMMARY

Experienced Software Engineer specializing in Full Stack Web Development and Network Automation. Proficient in Java, Python, Ansible, Javascript, NodeJS, React, SQL, GCP, AWS, Kubernetes, and Docker. With a demonstrated ability to adapt to new technologies and exceptional record of inspiring teams through effective communication and leadership.

WORK EXPERIENCE

SDN & Network Automation Engineer Co-Op | Nokia (Ottawa, ON)

May 2023 - Aug 2023

- Spearheaded the development of a network data extraction and transfer solution using Python, Ansible, and Podman, boosted monitoring efficiency by 40%, and enhanced network performance across production sites by securely transferring critical system data.
- Developed an automation platform using React and Python, reducing infrastructure setup time from weeks to 15 minutes, increasing operational efficiency by 95%, and significantly enhancing demos, PoCs, and the sales cycle.

Software Engineer | Rapidops Solutions (Ahmedabad, India)

Jul 2021 - Aug 2022

- Led the design and development of key Salesmate CRM features, including a dynamic meeting scheduler, activity reminder, and integrated texting and calling functionalities, utilizing Angular, JavaScript, and NodeJS.
- Implemented REST APIs, Webhooks, Cron-jobs, and optimized database gueries within a Microservices architecture, leveraging Kubernetes for deployments and debugging using log analysis, while contributing to the entire Agile SDLC.
- Successfully migrated databases of over 6500 companies from MySQL to CockroachDB to enhance scalability.
- Adhered to clean code architecture and comprehensive testing using CucumberJS, reducing post-launch issues by 70% and improving overall system reliability and maintainability.

Software Engineer Intern | Rapidops Solutions (Ahmedabad, India)

Dec 2020 - Jun 2021

- Mastered a diverse range of technologies, including Python, Java, Javascript, NodeJS, MySQL, MongoDB, GCP, AWS, Kafka, Docker, Kubernetes, and many more through rigorous coursework, and consistently achieving top results.
- Demonstrated expertise through presentations and hands-on projects, such as a User Management System, an intuitive Tree View File Structure, and the HealthCard platform for managing health data online. See the projects

EDUCATION

Master of Applied Computing | Wilfrid Laurier University (Waterloo, ON) | GPA:11.6/12 B.Tech, Computer Engineering | Dharmsinh Desai University (Nadiad,India) | CPI:8.0/10 Sep 2022 – Jun 2024

Sep 2017 - Apr 2021

SKILLS

Programming Languages C#, C++, Java, Python, Shell Scripts, Bash

Web Technologies HTML, CSS, Javascript, Typescript

Frameworks Rest APIs, Microservices, gRPC, Angular, NodeJS, Kubernetes, Django

MySQL, CockroachDB, Oracle, Elasticsearch, MongoDB, Redis **Databases**

Git, Linux, Ansible, Postman, Cucumber, Docker, Jenkins, Android Studio Software, Tools & OS **Cloud Platforms** Amazon Web Services (AWS), Google Cloud Platform (GCP), Azure

PROJECTS

CloudDriven - Personal Digital Storage and Secure Sharing | MEAN Stack, Heroku, AWS

- A cutting-edge Personal Storage solution enables users to upload, download, and share files securely.
- Incorporated a user-friendly folder structure and introduced QR code functionality for effortless file sharing.

Helping Hands - Emergency Help and Safety System | Android Studio, Java, Firebase

- A life-saving Android application, dedicated to providing immediate assistance during critical situations.
- Empowered users to promptly communicate their emergencies and automatically notify nearby volunteers with live user locations via Google Maps, enhancing real-time responses and fostering community support.

ACHIEVEMENTS

Hackerrank Intermediate Problem Solving Certified

Hackerrank

Acquired advanced proficiency in Data Structures like HashMaps, Stacks, Queues, and Algorithms.

C & C++ Programming Language Certification

Certificate

Completed C & C++ programming languages course by an ISO 9001-certified company, Itronix Solutions.

CodeChef Online Competitive coding platform - 3 stars (1615 rating)

CodeChef

Participated in online competitive coding contests and solved over 100 problems to attain top ratings.